Guide to the National Education Association-Committees records, 1857-1996 NEA1003.RG
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
- Joint Committee of the NEA and American Legion, 1921-1971; Series 12; 0.5 Linear Feet
  - "Need a Lift to Educational Opportunities, Careers, Loans, Scholarship and Employment?", 1971; Series 12 (Box 1258, Folder 9)
  - Spring Meeting, May 1964; Series 12 (Box 1258, Folder 10)
  - Steps in Joint Committee Development, 1967-1968; Series 12 (Box 1258, Folder 11)
  - "Strengthening and Protecting our American Heritage Through Community-School Action", August 1965; Series 12 (Box 1258, Folder 12)
  - Structure and Procedures, 1970; Series 12 (Box 1258, Folder 13)
  - Students Gain Understanding of Methods Used by Governments, 1966; Series 12 (Box 1258, Folder 14)
  - "Teaching About Communism", 1962; Series 12 (Box 1258, Folder 15)
- Joint Committee of the NEA and American Library Association, 1906-1977; Series 13; 1 Linear Feet
  The Joint Committee of the NEA and the American Library Association was established in 1931, and became a joint committee in 1944. Since 1950, the Committee has increasingly functioned as a liaison and referral committee, with the special purposes of exploring and expediting joint action of the two associations in all the areas of education and librarianship where there are common concerns.
  Series contains materials created within the Joint Committee of the NEA and American Library Association. The files include general papers, publications and reports from the committee.
  - "Aids in the Selection of Materials for Children and Young People", 1952-1957; Series 13 (Box 1259, Folder 1)
  - ALA Bulletin, April 1957; Series 13 (Box 1259, Folder 2)
  - ALA Bulletin: Salute to the NEA, April, 1957; Series 13 (Box 3970, Folder 8)
  - A Basic Book Collection for Junior High Schools, 1956; series 13 (Box 4351, Folder 8)
  - "Book Selection for Children and Young People", 1945; Series 13 (Box 1259, Folder 3)
  - By Way of Introduction: A Book List, 1938 - 1947; series 13 (Box 4319, Folder 5)
  - The Copyright Primer for Librarians and Educators, 1987; series 13 (Box 4351, Folder 9)
  - "Elementary School Libraries", 1939; Series 13 (Box 1259, Folder 4)
  - Elementary School Library Standards, 1925; series 13 (Box 4319, Folder 6)
  - The Freedom to Read, May 1953; series 13 (Box 4383, Folder 15)
  - Guide and Scripts: Media Programs for Individual Schools, 1969; series 13 (Box 4319, Folder 7)
  - "Has Your Library Had a Check-Up Lately?", 1948; Series 13 (Box 1259, Folder 5)
  - Management Survey, 1954-1956; Series 13 (Box 1259, Folder 6)
  - "Materially Speaking", 1948; Series 13 (Box 1259, Folder 7)
  - Minutes, 1947-1960; Series 13 (Box 1259, Folder 8)
  - "Moving Freedom Forward", 1959; Series 13 (Box 1259, Folder 9)
  - NEA Handbook Reprints, 1945-1961; Series 13 (Box 1259, Folder 10)
  - "NEA Research Bulletin", October 1958; Series 13 (Box 1259, Folder 11)
  - The New Copyright Law: Questions Teachers and Librarians Ask, 1977; series 13 (Box 4400, Folder 15)
  - The Paperback Goes to School: A Selected List of High and Junior High School Titles, 1963-1965; series 13 (Box 4319, Folder 8)
  - Papers, 1956-1958; Series 13 (Box 1259, Folder 12)
  - Papers, 1959; Series 13 (Box 1259, Folder 13)
  - Papers, 1960-1968; Series 13 (Box 1259, Folder 14)
  - Papers, 1974; Series 13 (Box 1259, Folder 15)
  - "The Price of Wisdom", 1947; Series 13 (Box 1259, Folder 16)
  - Report on Instruction in Library Administration in Normal Schools - Prepared by Elizabeth Baldwin, July 1906; series 13 (Box 4319, Folder 9)
  - Publications, 1937-1958; Series 13 (Box 1259, Folder 17)
  - School Library Studies and Research, October 1936; series 13 (Box 4319, Folder 10)
  - Schools and Public Libraries: Working Together in School Library Service, 1941; series 13 (Box 4319, Folder 11)
  - "Standards for School Library Programs", 1960; Series 13 (Box 1259, Folder 18)
  - Suggested Questions for Fall Meeting 1947, September 2 1947; series 13 (Box 4494, Folder 9)
  - "Toward These Goals", 1948; Series 13 (Box 1259, Folder 19)
- Joint Committee of the NEA and American Medical Association, 1911-1985; Series 14; 7.5 Linear Feet
  The Joint Committee of the NEA and American Medical Association was established in 1911. The committee was formed to work on problems and issues related to the school health program.
  Series contains materials created within the Joint Committee of the NEA and American Medical Association. The files include the papers of John H. Cooper and Edward Mileff. The series contains correspondence, notebooks, resolutions, summary reports and publications resulting from the committees work.
  Some highlights of these records include size charts for both boys and girls and related medical forms used by educators during the years. Also of interest are the "Sex Education Series" materials, which demonstrate early forays into sex education by educators and the NEA.
  - Answers to Health Questions in Physical Education, 1959, 1970; series 14 (Box 4319, Folder 12)
  - Approaching Adulthood, 1973; series 14 (Box 4319, Folder 13)
  - As Others See Us, 1959; series 14 (Box 4319, Folder 14)
  - Cooper, John H.-AASA Resolutions, Platform, Constitution, Bylaws, and Ethics, 1966; Series 14; Cooper, John H. (Box 1260, Folder 1)
  - Conserving the Sight of School Children, 1925-1935; Series 14 (Box 3970, Folder 1)
  - Cooper, John H.-Appointments, 1964-1965; Series 14; Cooper, John H. (Box 1260, Folder 2)
  - Cooper, John H.-Archives Transfer, 1970-1971; Series 14; Cooper, John H. (Box 1260, Folder 3)
  - Cooper, John H.-Biographical Information, 1969; Series 14; Cooper, John H. (Box 1260, Folder 4)
  - Cooper, John H.-Budget, Chart of Accounts, 1972; Series 14; Cooper, John H. (Box 1260, Folder 5)
  - Cooper, John H.-"Children", 1985; Series 14; Cooper, John H. (Box 1260, Folder 6)
  - Cooper, John H.-Committee Members, 1971-1974; Series 14; Cooper, John H. (Box 1260, Folder 7)
  - Cooper, John H.-Correspondence, 1962; Series 14; Cooper, John H. (Box 1260, Folder 8)
  - Cooper, John H.-Correspondence, 1963; Series 14; Cooper, John H. (Box 1260, Folder 9)
  - Cooper, John H.-Correspondence, 1964; Series 14; Cooper, John H. (Box 1260, Folder 10)
  - Cooper, John H.-Correspondence, 1965; Series 14; Cooper, John H. (Box 1260, Folder 11)
  - Cooper, John H.-Correspondence, 1966; Series 14; Cooper, John H. (Box 1260, Folder 12)
  - Cooper, John H.-Correspondence, 1968; Series 14; Cooper, John H. (Box 1261, Folder 1)
  - Cooper, John H.-Correspondence, 1969; Series 14; Cooper, John H. (Box 1261, Folder 2)
  - Cooper, John H.-Correspondence, 1970; Series 14; Cooper, John H. (Box 1261, Folder 3)
  - Cooper, John H.-Correspondence [file 1/2], 1971; Series 14; Cooper, John H. (Box 1261, Folder 4)
  - Cooper, John H.-Correspondence [file 2/2], 1971; Series 14; Cooper, John H. (Box 1261, Folder 5)
  - Cooper, John H.-Correspondence, 1972; Series 14; Cooper, John H. (Box 1262, Folder 1)
  - Cooper, John H.-Correspondence [file 1/2], 1973; Series 14; Cooper, John H. (Box 1262, Folder 2)
  - Cooper, John H.-Correspondence [file 2/2], 1973; Series 14; Cooper, John H. (Box 1262, Folder 3)
  - Cooper, John H.-Correspondence, 1974; Series 14; Cooper, John H. (Box 1262, Folder 4)
  - Cooper, John H.-Correspondence, 1974-1975; Series 14; Cooper, John H. (Box 1262, Folder 5)
  - Cooper, John H.-Department of Classroom Teachers, "Platforms and Resolutions", 1964-1965; Series 14; Cooper, John H. (Box 1263, Folder 1)
  - Cooper, John H.-Early Childhood Education, 1972; Series 14; Cooper, John H. (Box 1263, Folder 2)
  - Cooper, John H.-"Exercise Fitness", 1964; Series 14; Cooper, John H. (Box 1263, Folder 3)
  - Cooper, John H.-Expenses, 1973; Series 14; Cooper, John H. (Box 1263, Folder 4)
  - Cooper, John H.-Guidelines for Athletic Programs for Women, circa 1965; Series 14; Cooper, John H. (Box 1263, Folder 5)
  - Cooper, John H.-"Health Education" Revision Meeting, 1972-1973; Series 14; Cooper, John H. (Box 1263, Folder 6)
  - Cooper, John H.-Joint Committee Minutes, 1974-1975; Series 14; Cooper, John H. (Box 1263, Folder 7)
  - Cooper, John H.-Liaison Responsibilities, 1959-1973; Series 14; Cooper, John H. (Box 1263, Folder 8)
  - Cooper, John H.-MAIC Inquiries, 1972; Series 14; Cooper, John H. (Box 1263, Folder 9)
  - Cooper, John H.-Materials Mailed to the Committee, 1972; Series 14; Cooper, John H. (Box 1263, Folder 10)
  - Cooper, John H.-Meeting, November 1971-May 1972; Series 14; Cooper, John H. (Box 1263, Folder 11)
  - Cooper, John H.-Meeting, February 1975-July 1975; Series 14; Cooper, John H. (Box 1263, Folder 12)
  - Cooper, John H.-Minutes, 1911-1942; Series 14; Cooper, John H. (Box 1263, Folder 13)
  - Cooper, John H.-Notebooks, 1971; Series 14; Cooper, John H. (Box 1263, Folder 14)
  - Cooper, John H.-Notebooks, 1972; Series 14; Cooper, John H. (Box 1264, Folder 1)
  - Cooper, John H.-Notebooks [file 1/2], 1974-1975; Series 14; Cooper, John H. (Box 1264, Folder 2)
  - Cooper, John H.-Notebooks [file 2/2], 1974-1975; Series 14; Cooper, John H. (Box 1264, Folder 3)
  - Cooper, John H.-Problems of Homosexuality Subcommittee, 1962; Series 14; Cooper, John H. (Box 1264, Folder 4)
  - Cooper, John H.-Publications, 1962-1971; Series 14; Cooper, John H. (Box 1264, Folder 5)
  - Cooper, John H.-Publications Agreement, 1971; Series 14; Cooper, John H. (Box 1264, Folder 6)
  - Cooper, John H.-Quackery Booklet, 1967-1970; Series 14; Cooper, John H. (Box 1264, Folder 7)
  - Cooper, John H.-Quality of Life Conference, 1971; Series 14; Cooper, John H. (Box 1264, Folder 8)
  - Cooper, John H.-Quality of Life II Conference-The Middle Years, 1973-1974; Series 14; Cooper, John H. (Box 1264, Folder 9)
  - Cooper, John H.-Questionnaire, 1966; Series 14; Cooper, John H. (Box 1264, Folder 10)
  - Cooper, John H.-Recognition, 1971-1973; Series 14; Cooper, John H. (Box 1264, Folder 11)
  - Cooper, John H.-Resolutions, 1966-1973; Series 14; Cooper, John H. (Box 1265, Folder 1)
  - Cooper, John H.-Resolutions, 1967-1974; Series 14; Cooper, John H. (Box 1265, Folder 2)
  - Cooper, John H.-Resolutions, 1968-1971; Series 14; Cooper, John H. (Box 1265, Folder 3)
  - Cooper, John H.-Resolutions and Recommendations, 1961-1962; Series 14; Cooper, John H. (Box 1265, Folder 4)
  - Cooper, John H.-"Resolutions and Recommendations of the Joint Committee, Appendix II" (Ann Nolte), 1967; Series 14; Cooper, John H. (Box 1265, Folder 5)
  - Cooper, John H.-School Health Services Revision [file 1/2], 1961-1965; Series 14; Cooper, John H. (Box 1265, Folder 6)
  - Cooper, John H.-School Health Services Revision [file 2/2], 1961-1965; Series 14; Cooper, John H. (Box 1265, Folder 7)
  - Cooper, John H.-"Schools and Mental Health", 1964; Series 14; Cooper, John H. (Box 1266, Folder 1)
  - Cooper, John H.-"Statement of Policies for Competition in Girls and Women's Sports", 1964; Series 14; Cooper, John H. (Box 1266, Folder 2)
  - Cooper, John H.-Stationery, 1973-1974; Series 14; Cooper, John H. (Box 1266, Folder 3)
  - Cooper, John H.-Status as Committee, 1971-1972; Series 14; Cooper, John H. (Box 1266, Folder 4)
  - Cooper, John H.-Subcommittees, 1961-1963; Series 14; Cooper, John H. (Box 1266, Folder 5)
  - Cooper, John H.-Suggested School Health Policies Revision, 1962-1964; Series 14; Cooper, John H. (Box 1266, Folder 6)
  - Cooper, John H.-Summary of Education Data, A Course in Human Sexuality, 1973; Series 14; Cooper, John H. (Box 1266, Folder 7)
  - Cooper, John H.-Summary Reports, 1960-1965; Series 14; Cooper, John H. (Box 1266, Folder 8)
  - Cooper, John H.-Summary Reports, 1963-1966; Series 14; Cooper, John H. (Box 1266, Folder 9)
  - Cooper, John H.-Summary Resolutions, 1953-1973; Series 14; Cooper, John H. (Box 1266, Folder 10)
  - Cooper, John H.-"Three Books on School Health", circa 1958; Series 14; Cooper, John H. (Box 1266, Folder 11)
  - Cooper, John H.-Transaction Register, 1973; Series 14; Cooper, John H. (Box 1266, Folder 12)
  - Cooper, John H.-"Why Health Education?", 1964-1965; Series 14; Cooper, John H. (Box 1266, Folder 13)
  - Facts Aren't Enough, 1959, 1973; series 14 (Box 4319, Folder 15)
  - Finding Yourself, 1955, 1976; series 14 (Box 4319, Folder 16)
  - Functions and Purpose, 1950-1964; Series 14 (Box 1267, Folder 1)
  - General Information, 1911-1913; Series 14 (Box 1267, Folder 2)
  - General Information, 1914-1916; Series 14 (Box 1267, Folder 3)
  - General Information, 1917-1918; Series 14 (Box 1267, Folder 4)
  - General Information, 1919; Series 14 (Box 1267, Folder 5)
  - General Information, 1922-1927; Series 14 (Box 1267, Folder 6)
  - Golden Anniversary, 1961; Series 14 (Box 1267, Folder 7)
  - Health Appraisal of School Children, 1948-1970; Series 14 (Box 3970, Folder 2)
  - Health Aspects of the School Lunch Program, 1957, 1962; series 14 (Box 4319, Folder 17)
  - Health Charts, 1920, 1928; series 14 (Box 4320, Folder 1)
  - Health Education: A Program for Public Schools and Teacher Training Institutions, 1924; series 14 (Box 4320, Folder 2)
  - "Health Education and Sex/Family Life Education", 1967; Series 14 (Box 1267, Folder 8)
  - Health Essentials for Rural School Children, 1921; series 14 (Box 4320, Folder 3)
  - Health Examination of School Personnel, 1960; series 14 (Box 4320, Folder 4)
  - Health Improvement in Rural Schools, 1922; series 14 (Box 4320, Folder 5)
  - Health Problems in Education, July 1923; series 14 (Box 4320, Folder 6)
  - Health of School Personnel, 1964; series 14 (Box 4320, Folder 7)
  - Health Service in City Schools of the U.S., 1922; series 14 (Box 4320, Folder 8)
  - History of the Joint Committee on Health Problems in Education, 1963-1965; Series 14 (Box 1267, Folder 9)
  - Inherent Responsibilities of the School Health Education Program, 1941; Series 14 (Box 1267, Folder 10)
  - Issued Statements, 1938-1948; Series 14 (Box 1267, Folder 11)
  - Institutions Offering Programs of Specialization in Health Education for Schools, Colleges, Communities at the Undergraduate and Graduate Levels and Schools of Public Health, 1967-1970; series 14 (Box 4320, Folder 9)
  - Learning about Love, 1955; series 14 (Box 4320, Folder 10)
  - Mental Health and School Health Services Adapted from a Chapter in the Revised Edition of "School Health Services", 1965; series 14 (Box 4320, Folder 11)
  - Mental Hygiene in the Classroom, 1939, 1954; Series 14 (Box 3970, Folder 3)
  - Mileff, Edward-Joint Committee [file 1/2], 1967-1969; Series 14; Mileff, Edward (Box 1267, Folder 12)
  - Mileff, Edward-Joint Committee [file 2/2], 1967-1969; Series 14; Mileff, Edward (Box 1268, Folder 1)
  - Mileff, Edward-Notebook, 1966-1967; Series 14; Mileff, Edward (Box 1268, Folder 2)
  - Mileff, Edward-Notebook [file 1/2], 1969-1970; Series 14; Mileff, Edward (Box 1268, Folder 3)
  - Mileff, Edward-Notebook [file 2/2], 1969-1970; Series 14; Mileff, Edward (Box 1268, Folder 4)
  - Mileff, Edward-Notebook [file 1/2], 1969-1970; Series 14; Mileff, Edward (Box 1268, Folder 5)
  - Mileff, Edward-Notebook [file 2/2], 1969-1970; Series 14; Mileff, Edward (Box 1269, Folder 1)
  - Minimum Health Requirements for Rural Schools, 1920; series 14 (Box 4320, Folder 12)
  - Minutes [file 1/3], 1911-1974; Series 14 (Box 1269, Folder 2)
  - Minutes [file 2/3], 1911-1974; Series 14 (Box 1269, Folder 3)
  - Minutes [file 3/3], 1911-1974; Series 14 (Box 1269, Folder 4)
  - The Nurse in the School, 1940, 1955; Series 14 (Box 3970, Folder 4)
  - A Nutritional Program for Schools, ca. 1947; series 14 (Box 4320, Folder 13)
  - Papers [file 1/3], 1965-1968; Series 14 (Box 1270, Folder 1)
  - Papers [file 2/3], 1965-1968; Series 14 (Box 1270, Folder 2)
  - Papers [file 3/3], 1965-1968; Series 14 (Box 1270, Folder 3)
  - Parents Responsibility, 1970-1976; series 14 (Box 4320, Folder 14)
  - Publications-"The Administration of the School Health Program", 1932; Series 14 (Box 1270, Folder 4)
  - Publications-"Answers to Health Questions in Physical Education", 1970; Series 14 (Box 1270, Folder 5)
  - Publications-"As Others See Us", 1959; Series 14 (Box 1270, Folder 6)
  - Publications-"Conserving the Sight of School Children", 1925-1928; Series 14 (Box 1270, Folder 7)
  - Publications-"Health Appraisal of School Children", 1948-1969; Series 14 (Box 1270, Folder 8)
  - Publications-"Health Aspects of the School Lunch Program", 1956-1962; Series 14 (Box 1271, Folder 1)
  - Publications-"Health Charts", 1928; Series 14 (Box 1271, Folder 2)
  - Publications-"Health Conditions Affecting the Personality of School Youth", 1952; Series 14 (Box 1271, Folder 3)
  - Publications-"Health of School Personnel", 1964; Series 14 (Box 1271, Folder 4)
  - Publications-Height-Weight Charts, 1947-1975; Series 14 (Box 1271, Folder 5)
  - Publications List, undated; series 14 (Box 4383, Folder 16)
  - Publications-"Mental Hygiene in the Classroom", 1939-1953; Series 14 (Box 1271, Folder 6)
  - Publications-Physical Growth Record for Boys and Girls, circa 1950; Series 14 (Box 1271, Folder 7)
  - Publications-"A Physical Growth Record for Use in Elementary and High Schools", 1949; Series 14 (Box 1271, Folder 8)
  - Publications-School Health Records, circa 1970; Series 14 (Box 1271, Folder 9)
  - Publications-"Suggested Health Policies", 1945-1966; Series 14 (Box 1271, Folder 10)
  - Reports, 1912-1938; Series 14 (Box 1271, Folder 11)
  - Reports, 1922-1948; Series 14 (Box 1271, Folder 12)
  - Resolution [Extension of congratulations to the Committee on it's Golden Annivesary], January 21, 1961; Series 14 (Box 3301, Folder 4)
  - Resolutions-Miscellaneous Information, 1962-1972; Series 14 (Box 1271, Folder 13)
  - Rural School Survey Forms, 1912-1913; Series 14 (Box 1271, Folder 14)
  - "Sanitary Requirements for School Lunches", 1953; Series 14 (Box 1271, Folder 15)
  - "Schedule Fatigue in School Children", 1951; Series 14 (Box 1271, Folder 16)
  - School Health Education: A Call for Action! Implications of the Nationwide Study of Health Instruction in the Public Schools, 1961-1963: The School Health Education Study, 1965; series 14 (Box 4320, Folder 15)
  - "Selections from Addresses" by Thomas D. Wood, 1932; Series 14 (Box 1271, Folder 17)
  - Sex Education Series, circa 1960; Series 14 (Box 1272, Folder 1)
  - Sex Education Series Sheet, undated; series 14 (Box 4320, Folder 16)
  - Sex Education Series-"Approaching Adulthood", 1964-1969; Series 14 (Box 1272, Folder 2)
  - Sex Education Series-"Approaching Adulthood", 1973; Series 14 (Box 1272, Folder 3)
  - Sex Education Series-"Facts Aren't Enough", 1955; Series 14 (Box 1272, Folder 4)
  - Sex Education Series-"Facts Aren't Enough", 1955-1960; Series 14 (Box 1272, Folder 5)
  - Sex Education Series-"Facts Aren't Enough", 1962-1964; Series 14 (Box 1272, Folder 6)
  - Sex Education Series-"Finding Yourself", 1960-1968; Series 14 (Box 1272, Folder 7)
  - Sex Education Series-"Finding Yourself", 1970-1976; Series 14 (Box 1272, Folder 8)
  - Sex Education Series-"Parent's Privilege", 1958; Series 14 (Box 1272, Folder 9)
  - Sex Education Series-"Parent's Responsibility", 1962-1970; Series 14 (Box 1272, Folder 10)
  - Sex Education Series-"Preparation for Marriage", 1960; Series 14 (Box 1272, Folder 11)
  - Sex Education Series-"A Story About You", 1960-1962; Series 14 (Box 1272, Folder 12)
  - Sex Education Series-"A Story About You", 1964-1975; Series 14 (Box 1272, Folder 13)
  - Sleep and Children: The Application of Our Knowledge about Sleep to the Needs of Children and Youth, 1958; series 14 (Box 4320, Folder 17)
  - A Story About You, 1955, 1975; series 14 (Box 4320, Folder 18)
  - Student Health Pamphlets, 1925-1952; Series 14 (Box 3970, Folder 5)
  - Suggested School Health Policies, 1946 - 1966; 1963-1966; series 14 (Box 4320, Folder 19)
  - Why Health Education?, 1965; series 14 (Box 4320, Folder 20)
- Joint Committee of the NEA and American Teachers Association, 1941-1977; Series 15; 1.5 Linear Feet
  Authorized in 1926 as the Committee on Educational Problems in Colored Schools, this committee became, in 1928, a joint committee of the NEA and the National Association of Teachers in Colored Schools which became the American Teachers Association in 1939.
  The Joint Committee was designed to stimulate cooperative use of the two organizations' resources in energetic approaches to professional problems arising from racial and human relationships in American schools.
  Series contains materials created within the Joint Committee of the NEA and American Teachers Association. The files include minutes of meetings, merger notes, and papers on the Project on Intergroup Education.
  - Correspondence-Issues at State-Local Affiliate Levels, 1945-1964; Series 15 (Box 1273, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence and Draft Copies of Studies, 1947-1954; Series 15 (Box 1273, Folder 2)
  - Guide for Using a Kit on Intergroup Education, 1951; series 15 (Box 4320, Folder 21)
  - Kit on Intergroup Education, 1951-1956; Series 15 (Box 1273, Folder 3)
  - Leaders' Guide to the Use and Study of Materials on Intergroup Education, 1954; Series 15 (Box 4593, Folder 2)
  - Letter Concerning Treatment of Negroes in Textbooks, March 22, 1945; Series 15 (Box 3970, Folder 6)
  - Meeting, January 1951-October 1954; Series 15 (Box 1273, Folder 4)
  - Meeting (Chicago, IL), July 1955; Series 15 (Box 1273, Folder 5)
  - Meeting, October 1955; Series 15 (Box 1273, Folder 6)
  - Meeting (Portland, OR), July 1956; Series 15 (Box 1274, Folder 1)
  - Meeting (Philadelphia, PA), June 1957; Series 15 (Box 1274, Folder 2)
  - Meeting, January 1958; Series 15 (Box 1274, Folder 3)
  - Meeting (Cleveland, OH), July 1958; Series 15 (Box 1274, Folder 4)
  - Meeting, January 1959; Series 15 (Box 1274, Folder 5)
  - Meeting (Saint Louis, MO), June 1959; Series 15 (Box 1274, Folder 6)
  - Meeting, January 1960; Series 15 (Box 1274, Folder 7)
  - Meeting (Los Angeles, CA), June 1960; Series 15 (Box 1274, Folder 8)
  - Meeting, January 1961; Series 15 (Box 1274, Folder 9)
  - Meeting, January 1962; Series 15 (Box 1274, Folder 10)
  - Meeting (Denver, CO), July 1962; Series 15 (Box 1274, Folder 11)
  - Meeting, January 1963; Series 15 (Box 1274, Folder 12)
  - Meeting (Detroit, MI), July 1963; Series 15 (Box 1274, Folder 13)
  - Meeting, January 1964; Series 15 (Box 1274, Folder 14)
  - Meeting (Seattle, WA), June 1964; Series 15 (Box 1274, Folder 15)
  - Meeting, January 1965; Series 15 (Box 1274, Folder 16)
  - Meeting (New York, NY), June 1965; Series 15 (Box 1274, Folder 17)
  - Meeting, January 1966; Series 15 (Box 1275, Folder 1)
  - Meeting (Miami Beach, FL), June 1966; Series 15 (Box 1275, Folder 2)
  - Merger, 1960-1977; Series 15 (Box 1275, Folder 3)
  - Minutes, 1941-1950; Series 15 (Box 1275, Folder 4)
  - Project on Intergroup Education-Contact List, 1954-1955; Series 15 (Box 1275, Folder 5)
  - Project on Intergroup Education-Promotion and Publicity Activities, 1955; Series 15 (Box 1275, Folder 6)
  - "Sources of Instructional Materials on Negroes", 1946; Series 15 (Box 1275, Folder 7)
  - Study on the Status of the Education of Negros Parts I and II, January 1954; series 15 (Box 4321, Folder 1)
  - Subcommittee on Textbooks and Textbook Materials, 1941-1949; Series 15 (Box 1275, Folder 8)
- Joint Committee of the NEA and Magazine Publishers Association, 1958-1972; Series 16; 0.75 Linear Feet
  The Joint Committee of the NEA and the Magazine Publishers Association was created in 1954 at the NEA Annual Convention in New York City. The Committee was charged with developing national joint programs, investigating areas where united action can serve useful purposes for both groups, and cooperating in reporting to the public matters pertaining to education.
  Series contains materials created within the Joint Committee of the NEA and Magazine Publishers Association. The files include papers, publications, a small history of the committee, and photos.